export const MUSICA2020 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The last section of the first movement of a sonata is the",
A: "coda",
B: "exposition",
C: "development",
D: "recapitulation",
answer: "A. coda",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Songs sung to mourn the dead are",
A: "patriotic",
B: "dirges",
C: "recreational",
D: "lullabies",
answer: "B. dirges",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. Which of the following musicians recorded the song Respect?",
A: "Jimmy Cliff",
B: "Aretha Franklin",
C: "Mighty Sparrow",
D: "Duke Ellington",
answer: "B. Aretha Franklin",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. The time signature for three quaver beats in a bar is",
A: "38",
B: "32",
C: "316",
D: "34",
answer: "C. 3/8",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Which of the following oratorios contains The Heavens are Telling?",
A: "Saul",
B: "Creation",
C: "Samson",
D: "Elijah",
answer: "B. Creation",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. When a double flat is applied to the note ‘B’, it enharmonically becomes",
A: "G sharp",
B: "C",
C: "A flat",
D: "A",
answer: "C. A flat",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. What is the relative minor of the major key above?",
A: "G",
B: "F",
C: "E",
D: "D",
answer: "C. E",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. The music above modulates to",
A: "G major",
B: "D major",
C: "C major",
D: "B major",
answer: "A. G major",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. Which of the following musicians is noted for his traditional guitar style?",
A: "Daniel Amponsah",
B: "Kwamina Pra",
C: "Vinoko Akpalu",
D: "George Darko",
answer: "A. Daniel Amponsah",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Yuga belongs to a class of instruments called",
A: "aerophones",
B: "idiophones",
C: "chordophones",
D: "membranophones",
answer: "A. aerophones",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. The music is supposed to begin in a",
A: "moderately loud manner",
B: "loud manner",
C: "soft manner",
D: "moderately soft manner",
answer: "C. soft manner",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The form of the music is",
A: "rando",
B: "strophic",
C: "ternary",
D: "binary",
answer: "C. ternary",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The music begins",
A: "with a semibreve",
B: "with a syncopation",
C: "on anacrusic beat",
D: "on a strong beat",
answer: "C. on anacrusic beat",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. For how many instruments is the music written",
A: "Four",
B: "Three",
C: "Two",
D: "One",
answer: "B. Three",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The symbol in the guitar part indicates",
A: "trill",
B: "strumming",
C: "arpeggios",
D: "pause",
answer: "B. strumming",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Which of the following illustrates the range of the voice part",
A: "*******************************",
B: "*******************************",
C: "*******************************",
D: "*******************************",
answer: "Z. zzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzzz",
correctLetter: "Z",
correctOption: 9,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. The music ends in",
A: "an interrupted cadence",
B: "a plagal cadence",
C: "an imperfect cadence",
D: "a perfect cadence",
answer: "D. a perfect cadence",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The music is in",
A: "simple quadruple time",
B: "compound quadruple time",
C: "simple duple time",
D: "compound duple time",
answer: "A. simple quadruple time",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The compositional device commonly used in the bass part of the piano is",
A: "repetition",
B: "scales",
C: "interlocking thirds",
D: "broken chords",
answer: "D. broken chords",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. In performing the last two bars of the piano part in terms of dynamics, the sound should",
A: "become soft suddenly",
B: "become loud suddenly",
C: "increase gradually",
D: "decrease gradually",
answer: "D. decrease gradually",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The choral work Mawu Nye Lolo was composed by",
A: "J. M. T. Dosoo",
B: "K. K. Avortri",
C: "W. K. Blege",
D: "R. GK. Ndor",
answer: "C. W. K. Blege",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The song Hadzidzi Nugae was composed by",
A: "Michael KofiAmissah",
B: "Atta Annan Mensah",
C: "Nicholas Zinzerdorf Nayo",
D: "Robert George Komla Ndo",
answer: "B. Atta Annan Mensah",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. Which of the following minor keys has three flats as its key signature?",
A: "E flat",
B: "E",
C: "C flat",
D: "C",
answer: "A. E flat",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. The above dominant 7th chord in C major is in",
A: "root position",
B: "3rd inversion",
C: "2nd inversion",
D: "1st inversion",
answer: "A. root position",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The last note of the music above is",
A: "E",
B: "D",
C: "C",
D: "B",
answer: "C. C",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The staff above is",
A: "treble staff",
B: "alto staff",
C: "tenor staff",
D: "bass staff",
answer: "D. bass staff",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. African instruments which produce sounds through air column are",
A: "idiophones",
B: "membranophones",
C: "chordophones",
D: "aerophones",
answer: "D. aerophones",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. The opening section of the sonata allegro form is the",
A: "coda",
B: "exposition",
C: "development",
D: "recapitulation",
answer: "B. exposition",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Which of the following musicians performs traditional choral music?",
A: "Samuel Asare Bediako",
B: "Gyede Blay Ambolley",
C: "Yaa Adusa",
D: "Daddy Lumba",
answer: "A. Samuel Asare Bediako",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Which of the following themes is peculiar to Blues music?",
A: "Lies",
B: "Love",
C: "Politics",
D: "Poverty",
answer: "B. Love",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Who among the following musicians is recognised as the father of Ghanaian Art Music?",
A: "C. Graves",
B: "J. H. Nketia",
C: "E. Amu",
D: "Riverson I.",
answer: "C. E. Amu",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. C. K. Mann a popular musician in Ghana is a",
A: "violinist",
B: "pianist",
C: "guitarist",
D: "trumpeter",
answer: "C. guitarist",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Fela Anikulapo Kuti was",
A: "a gospel musician",
B: "a popular musician",
C: "a traditional musician",
D: "an art musician",
answer: "B. a popular musician",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. In E minor, the note marked ‘X’ above is the",
A: "subdominant",
B: "mediant",
C: "supertonic",
D: "tonic",
answer: "C. supertonic",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. The scale illustrated above is",
A: "chromatic",
B: "melodic minor",
C: "natural minor",
D: "major",
answer: "B. melodic minor",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Yen Ara Asase Ni composed by Ephraim Amu teaches",
A: "sympathy",
B: "ethnicity",
C: "honesty",
D: "patriotism",
answer: "D. patriotism",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Who among the following is a traditional musician?",
A: "Stella Doughan",
B: "Kweku Acquaah Harrison",
C: "Vinoko Akpalu",
D: "Ken Kafui",
answer: "C. Vinoko Akpalu",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. When a diminished 4th is inverted, it becomes",
A: "a perfect 5th",
B: "a minor 4th",
C: "an augmented 5th",
D: "a major 6th",
answer: "A. a perfect 5th",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Which of the following playing techniques is associated with string performance?",
A: "Pedalling",
B: "Overblowing",
C: "Double stopping",
D: "Double tonguing",
answer: "C. Double stopping",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The call and response form of music is",
A: "yodeling",
B: "hocket",
C: "homophonic",
D: "autiphonal",
answer: "D. antiphonal",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]